JOY EVANS

 Pearland, TX 77584
 □ 713-826-7449
 ■ joyevans@me.com

github.com/JoyE-HOU M joy-evans.medium.com in

linkedin.com/in/joy-evans

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with a passion for problem-solving. With nearly a decade-long background as a design consultant, my job was to work with nail-biting timelines with residential and commercial clients. This fast-paced environment taught me how to learn new products and software and effectively manage my time. Besides, working with at least 15 projects at different stages can quickly become overwhelming.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

C# | Angular | Ruby | Rails | Javascript | React | SQL | CSS | HTML | Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Apollo - Github

Apollo is a Social media app that allows you to collaborate with other users to create storyboard posts. Designed with user experience and social elements in mind Apollo is revolutionizing the way friends interact online. Features include posting, adding to other users' posts, commenting, liking, saving profile information, and more.

- Was team lead in implementing new features
- Worked on DevOps Team
- Refactored existing source code
- Debugged and tested source code
- Persisted data to SQLServer DB

Environment:

AWS RDS, Kubernetes, SQL Server, Entity Framework Core, ASP.NET Core Web API, Angular 10, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Swagger, Git, TypeScript, C#, Helm

Store REST API - Github

The Store API is a RESTful API that helps customers purchase products from your business. Designed with functionality that would make virtual shopping much simpler! Customer features include account creation, order placements, and order history. It also comes with admin functionality that let's store owners replenish inventory and view the specific store's order history!

- Refactored source code to ASP.NET Core Web API
- Use Docker to dockerize application
- Created an Entity-Relationship (ER) Diagram flowchart
- Implemented xUnit for testing needs
- Created DB using AWS RDS and SQLServer DB
- Persisted data to SQLServer DB
- Implemented XML documentation and Exception Handling
- Managed tasks using Kanban board on Trello

Environment:

C# Programming, SQL, xUnit Testing, ASP.NET Core Web API, ADO.NET, AWS RDS, Elastic Beanstalk, Git, DevOps

HealthSquad - Github | Demo

A meditation tracker app for everyday users needing help managing all current prescriptions.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and b-crypt to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Compose a PDF file of current medications to download onto the computer

Environment:

Ruby on Rails, React

EXPERIENCE

.NET Software Developer | Revature | Pearland, TX

12/2021 - 07/2022

Participated in a twelve-week training program that focused on .NET technologies and workflows including:

- C# & Angular
- TDD through unit testing using xUnit
- Kubernetes, AWS RDS & Docker
- Orchestrating and maintaining a CI/CD pipeline using Github Actions
- Managed data persistence with PostgreSQL
- Controlled source code using Git through a CLI

Design Consultant | SpaceManager Closets | Houston, TX

07/2019 - 07/2020

- Collaborate with clients on designing spaces needing more functional spaces by increasing both linear space and aesthetic appeal
- Supervised installations and reviewed requests made by the customer with the engineers and installers prior to installation

Design Consultant | Floor & Decor | Sugar Land, TX

10/2017 - 06/2019

- Integrate findings and knowledge of interior design to formulate a plan and sell the appropriate products to complete the customer's project
- Met with customers to determine preferences, purpose, function, types of materials, and budget when planning interior and exterior environments

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Houston, TX 11/ 2020 - 04/2021

The Art Institute of Houston
Bachelor of Fine Arts, Interior Design

Houston, TX 03/2012

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Technology Associate: Software Development Fundamentals (MTA)

2022

Microsoft - 993079313